Guide to the Samuel A. Trufant papers
Louisiana Research Collection
Samuel A. Trufant papers 1900-1920
LaRC/Manuscripts Collection 205
1.00
0.5 linear foot
Louisiana Research Collection 202 Jones Hall 6801 Freret Street New Orleans, LA, URL: http://specialcollections.tulane.edu/archon Email: sbenjam@tulane.edu Phone: 504-865-5685
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access:
Collection is open to the public. No known restrictions.
Arrangement of Materials:
This collection is arranged by subject. It consists of 0.5 linear foot.
Scope and Contents
The papers in this collection are divided into three groups. The first group deals with the Crescent City Stock Yard and Slaughter House records (1900-1914). There are also financial records and production inventories of the company in which Mr. Trufant had the position of treasurer. The second group of papers revolves around the upkeep and repair of the levees in 1897, which was the concern of the Citizens Committee on Levees of which Mr. Trufant was Vice-Chairman. Papers from various business interests that Mr. Trufant was engaged in and a few personal papers make up the third group of documents.
Detailed List of Contents
- Samuel A. Trufant papers, 1900-1920; id62920 (Box 1)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter House papers, 1900-1904; id62927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1904; id62932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1905; id62934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1905; id62942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1905-1907; id62944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1908-1909; id62945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1910; id62947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1910; id62958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1911; id62967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, undated; id62969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Crescent City stock yards and slaughter house papers, 1912-1914; id62970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Crescent city stock yards and slaughter house newspaper clippings, 1897-1910; id62979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Citizens Committee on Levees, 1879; id62985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Personal and business papers, 1879-1901; id63000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Personal and business papers, 1910-1912; id63016 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Personal and business papers, 1912; id63017 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Personal and business papers, 1913-1920; id82034 (Box 1, Folder 17)